Guide to the photograph album Iraq, Egypt, Yemen compiled by L. Wells from the Hisham Khatib Collection AD.MC.030_ref158
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection
1934 - 1936
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939
AD.MC.030_ref158
33 Leaves - 36 gelatin silver photographs
Created by officer Les Wells while he served with the Medical Service at the RAF General Hospital in Hinaidi as part of the "British Forces in Iraq" RAF Command and whilst he was stationed in Egypt between 1934 and 1936 - part of the Hisham Khatib Collection.
Object Digital copy only - ref158
Content Description
A photograph album containing 36 gelatin silver prints of sites and people in Iraq and Egypt between 1934 and 1936.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Aden, Yemen; Egypt; Regional/National Dress; Royal Air Force; Landscapes; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Military/Soldiers
- Front Cover of Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection, 1934-1936; ref158_000001; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Inside of the front cover of Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection, 1934-1936; ref158_000002; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  English Writing
- Aerial view of RAF Aboukir air base., 1934-1936; ref158_000003; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Royal Air Force; Coast; Military/Soldiers; Seas; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Abu Qir, Egypt; Landscapes
- A waterfall in Sulav, Northern Iraq, 1934-1936; ref158_000004; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Waterfalls; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Sulav, Kurdistan, Iraq
- A bridge over a river in Sulav, Iraq., 1934-1936; ref158_000005; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Bridges; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Iraq; English Writing; Rivers; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Sulav, Kurdistan, Iraq
- Zab River in Iraq, with mountains in the background., 1934-1936; ref158_000006; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Rivers; Iraq; Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; English Writing; Water; Great Zab River; Southern Kurdistan, Iraq
- A woman wearing a veil carrying a basket on her head, with boys surrounding her., 1934-1936; ref158_000007; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Women; Boys; Girls; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Outdoors; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Photographic Prints; Children; Group Portraits; Food; Workers
- Three men sitting outdoors, described as scribes/letter writers in AD_MC_044_ref11., 1934-1936; ref158_000008; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Outdoors; Men; Children; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Arabic Writing; English Writing; Furnishings; Signs/Signposts; Boys; Group Portraits
- Several men standing around two men sitting on the ground., 1934-1936; ref158_000009; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Men; Regional/National Dress; Outdoors; Outdoors; Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits
- A portrait of a man with a mustache wearing a keffiyeh., 1934-1936; ref158_000010; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Men; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress
- A man harvesting dates from a palm tree., 1934-1936; ref158_000011; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Palm Trees; Workers; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Men; Food
- Mausoleum of Umar Suhrawardi, Baghdad., 1934-1936; ref158_000012; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Tombs/Mausoleums; Buildings; Palm Trees; Baghdad, Iraq; Architecture; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cemeteries; Religious Sites
- Mausoleum of Umar Suhrawardi, Baghdad., 1934-1936; ref158_000013; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Tombs/Mausoleums; Architecture; Buildings; Baghdad, Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Cemeteries; Religious Sites
- A Nairn Transport vehicle crossing the Syrian desert., 1934-1936; ref158_000014; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Buses; Deserts; Transportation; Syria; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- An aerial view of Taq Kasra (Archway of Ctesiphon)., 1934-1936; ref158_000015; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Buildings; Architecture; Iraq; Deserts; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Landscapes
- A statue in the Antoniadis Garden in Alexandria, Egypt., 1934-1936; ref158_000016; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Gardens; Statues/Sculptures; Alexandria, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- A statue in the Antoniadis Garden in Alexandria, Egypt., 1934-1936; ref158_000017; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Statues/Sculptures; Gardens; Alexandria, Egypt; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- HMS Enterprise off the coast of Aden., 1934-1936; ref158_000018; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Military/Soldiers; Boats/Ships; Navy; Seas; Aden, Yemen; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- The mediterranean fleet in Alexandria harbour., 1934-1936; ref158_000019; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Seas; Boats/Ships; Ports; Coast; Alexandria, Egypt; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Mediterranean Sea; Transportation; Group Portraits; Landscapes
- Stanley bay in Alexandria., 1934-1936; ref158_000020; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Alexandria, Egypt; Beaches; Men; Advertisements; Shops; Buildings; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Advertisements; Signs/Signposts; Group Portraits
- Nouzha garden in Alexandria., 1934-1936; ref158_000021; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Egypt; English Writing; Gardens; Palm Trees
- Nouzha garden in Alexandria., 1934-1936; ref158_000022; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Portrait of a child leaning against a wall., 1934-1936; ref158_000023; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Girls; Children; Individual Portraits; Outdoors
- House on the wall, Montazah., 1934-1936; ref158_000024; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Alexandria, Egypt; Egypt; Buildings; Houses; Architecture
- House on the wall, Montazah., 1934-1936; ref158_000025; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; English Writing; Architecture; Buildings
- A body of water with trees and rocks in the background., 1934-1936; ref158_000026; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Landscapes; Water
- A boy and a girl standing outdoors., 1934-1936; ref158_000027; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Group Portraits; Children; Boys; Girls; Regional/National Dress; Outdoors
- A waterfall with a building in the background., 1934-1936; ref158_000028; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Waterfalls; Buildings; Landscapes
- A rocky hillside., 1934-1936; ref158_000029; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Landscapes
- Men and horses by a body of water., 1934-1936; ref158_000030; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Horses; Men; Water; Animals; Group Portraits
- A group of five men carrying guns., 1934-1936; ref158_000031; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Group Portraits; Guns; Horses; Turbans; Weapons; Swords/Knives; Regional/National Dress; Animals; Men
- A man riding a camel with the Pyramid of Khafre in the background., 1934-1936; ref158_000032; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Camels; Men; Palm Trees; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Animals; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Individual Portraits
- Great Sphinx of Giza., 1934-1936; ref158_000033; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Giza, Egypt; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Egypt; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Monuments/Memorials
- Blank Page, 1934-1936; ref158_000034; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Interior of RAF Halton House., 1934-1936; ref158_000035; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Architecture; Houses; Chandeliers; Furnishings; Aylesbury, England, UK; Furnishings; Military/Soldiers
- Blank Page, 1934-1936; ref158_000036; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Blank Page, 1934-1936; ref158_000037; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Blank Page, 1934-1936; ref158_000038; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Left: A concert poster for The Exiles. Right: A group of performers on stage wearing white tuxedos, including Les Wells at the piano (linked to AD_MC_046_ref49 in the album 'Iraq and Kurdistan - compiled by an RAF serviceman' and AD_MC_044_ref44 in 'Iraq and Kurdistan - compiled by L. Wells of RAF Hinaidi')., 1934-1936; ref158_000039; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Group Portraits; Men; Tuxedos; Bow Ties; Pianos; Musical Instruments; Performing Arts; Advertisements; Costumes; Theater
- Top: A group photo of men in uniform. Bottom: A street view., 1934-1936; ref158_000040; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Group Portraits; Outdoors; Men; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Architecture; Royal Air Force; Street Lamps
- Top: Aerial view of a harbour. Bottom: Ship leaving a harbour with covered cannons in the foreground., 1934-1936; ref158_000041; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; Boats/Ships; Military/Soldiers; Cannons; Seas; Architecture; Buildings; Weapons; Transportation; Ports
- Blank Page, 1934-1936; ref158_000042; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- A man in a chemistry lab with bottles on the shelf in the background., 1934-1936; ref158_000043; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Men; Lab Coats; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Scientific Equipment; Lab Coats; Laboratories; Individual Portraits
- Palm trees., 1934-1936; ref158_000044; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Unknown Locations; English Writing; Palm Trees
- Inside of the Back Cover, 1934-1936; ref158_000045; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)
- Back cover of Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells - Hisham Khatib Collection, 1934-1936; ref158_000046; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - ref158)